# Harsh Jha

Github: Harsheys21 | jha.harsh21@gmail.com | Linkedin: harshnjha | https://harsheys21.vercel.app/

#### **SUMMARY**

I am currently a Computer Science graduate student completing a thesis and researching within the fields of data management and machine learning. Outside of taking courses in Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and Databases, I have developed a comprehensive crime dashboard for the Santa Cruz Police Department to improve allocation of department resources and to provide more transparency of the crimes around campus. Overall my interest lies in exploring innovative technologies in AI and machine learning to drive future projects and continue growing in the field of software engineering.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Santa Cruz Police Department, Santa Cruz — Full Stack Developer

January 2024 - June 2024

- Developed a comprehensive crime dashboard to visualize crime data enabling police to track and identify trends and facilitate decision-making and resource allocation, ultimately increasing user engagement by 35%
- Created an interactive heat map, boosting resource allocation by 30% and improving optimal officer deployment
- Built Machine Learning models to categorize and predict crimes with over ~90% accuracy

## Association for Computing Machinery, Santa Cruz — Community Lead

January 2023 - February 2024

- Increased quarterly events by 80%, including activities and skill development workshops (AI, startups, etc.)
- Led partnership development with companies, such as Google, to connect students with opportunities & internships
- Cultivated partnerships with UCSC colleges, improving ACM's finances and visibility

# Petals Events & Decor LLC, San Jose — Front End Developer

July 2022 - August 2022 https://petalsevents.vercel.app/

- Developed Petals' responsive website using Material UI & React, optimizing loading speed and increasing responsiveness and professional branding contributing to 100+ additional clients within 6 months.

## **EDUCATION**

University of Ottawa — Computer Science B.S. (Thesis Program with Specialization in Applied AI)

# **SKILLS**

Web Development: Selenium | React | HTML & CSS | Javascript | Figma | AWS Lambda | AWS Amplify | PHP | Bootstrap

Databases: Neo4j | PostgreSQL | DynamoDB | Firebase | MySQL | SQL

Programming Skills: C/C++ | Python | Java | Assembly | C#

Tools: Git | UNIX | Windows | Jira | Latex | Docker | Vercel | Microsoft Power BI | Agile | Github | Unity

Machine Learning: PyTorch | TensorFlow | Keras | Numpy

Soft Skills: Communication | Teamwork | Time Management | Public Speaking

# **PROJECTS**

# StudyLink

#### React, CSS, Python, AWS: https://github.com/Harsheys21/Study-Link

- Developed a full-stack app addressing the challenge of post-campus study group formation and remote learning isolation

#### HTML, CSS, Mapbox: https://github.com/Harsheys21/Soteria

#### Soteria

 Created and coded the Soteria website with a focus on Santa Cruz safety, providing secure travel routes and featuring interactive maps for an enhanced user experience